<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Mower – Software Setup</title><link>/docs/software-setup/</link><description>Recent content in Software Setup on Open Mower</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/software-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Configuring Wi-Fi</title><link>/docs/software-setup/configuring-wifi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/software-setup/configuring-wifi/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="step-0-charge-the-robot">Step 0: Charge the Robot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make sure that the robot is turned on and fully charged, since the software installation will take some time. You can also do this step while the mower is charging in the docking station.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-1-search-the-hotspot">Step 1: Search the Hotspot&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="container-fluid m-0 p-0">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col">
&lt;p>Turn your mower on and wait for the Raspberry Pi to boot. The next step is to connect the Robot to your Wi-Fi network. This way it can download and install the latest OpenMower software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to do this, take any mobile device and search for Wi-Fi networks. Your robot should have opened a hotspot with the credentials you set earlier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default credentials are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SSID:&lt;/strong> openmower-somenumber&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Password:&lt;/strong> openmower&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Connect to the hotspot and the mobile device should ask you to &lt;em>sign-in into the network&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-3">
&lt;div>&lt;img src='connect_Wi-Fi_screen_1.png' width=250 />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h4 id="if-no-website-is-shown">If no website is shown:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If the mobile device does not automatically open the sign-in page for you, you can access it while being connected with the hotspot by navigating to the following URL in any browser: http://10.41.0.1/&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-2-enter-your-wi-fi-credentials">Step 2: Enter your Wi-Fi Credentials&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="container-fluid m-0 p-0">
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col">
&lt;p>On the screen, select your home Wi-Fi connection and enter your password. Then click connect. Your robot will connect to your network and the hotspot will disappear. If the connection fails, the hotspot will reopen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-3">
&lt;div>&lt;img src='connect_Wi-Fi_screen_2.png' width=250 />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="step-3-optional-check-connection">Step 3 (Optional): Check Connection&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Check the connection by using any other PC in your network and &lt;code>ping openmower.local&lt;/code>. This should be working. Alternatively, you can check if the device is connected by logging into your router.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-4-wait">Step 4: Wait&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If the connection is successful, the Raspberry Pi will download and install the latest OpenMower software automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This will take some time! Depending on your SD card and your internet connection give it up to 30 minutes!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know that the process was successful by looking at the RGB LED on your mainboard. It will either switch to &lt;em>RED-GREEN blinking&lt;/em> or a &lt;em>SOLID GREEN&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Record a Map</title><link>/docs/software-setup/record-a-map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/software-setup/record-a-map/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In this section, we finally drive the robot around and test if everything works as expected. Then we will record a map, and you can see the magic happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A smartphone or PC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modified robot connected to your network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OpenMower software running on the robot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Docking station modified and powered up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mower fully charged&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="step-1-check-the-gps">Step 1: Check the GPS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="gps_quality_indicator.jpg" alt="GPS Quality Indicator">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this step, put the mower into the docking station and turn it on. It should boot up and get to a solid green status LED.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is important that the mower is out in the open for the RTK GPS to work. Don&amp;rsquo;t try this indoors and don&amp;rsquo;t cover the mower.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open the OpenMower web app with any device by opening a browser and going to the following URL: &lt;a href="http://openmower.local:8080">http://openmower.local:8080&lt;/a>. If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, replace &lt;code>openmower.local&lt;/code> with your mower&amp;rsquo;s IP address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait for the GPS to find a position. This might take some time (up to 30 minutes).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the current GPS quality in the Open Mower app as shown in the graphic above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You need to have RTK Fixed&lt;/strong> for the following to work. If you don&amp;rsquo;t get a good GPS fix, you will need to check your RTK setup and configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="step-2-initialize-the-orientation">Step 2: Initialize the Orientation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the position, the robot also needs to know its orientation. Since we are not using a compass, the robot&amp;rsquo;s orientation is derived from its movement.
In order to initialize the orientation, you need to drive the robot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can either use the on-screen joystick in the Open Mower App or a gamepad connected via USB (hold the A button) to drive the robot.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
Don&amp;rsquo;t pick up the mower or the orientation will be lost again!
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Now drive the mower for at least 50m, do some straight lines and some figure eight patterns. Currently, the robot does not know the quality of its orientation estimate, but you can judge by driving and looking at the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The orientation is initialized correctly if:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When driving a straight line, the visualization also drives a straight line (no jumps)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When rotating in place, the visualization stays in place and doesn&amp;rsquo;t jump&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="step-3-record-a-simple-map">Step 3: Record a Simple Map&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this step, we will record a simple map. Keep it simple for the first tests and record your map as soon as you&amp;rsquo;re confident that everything works as expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map for the mower consists of three parts: the &lt;strong>docking position&lt;/strong>, at least one &lt;strong>mowing area&lt;/strong> and optionally &lt;strong>navigation areas&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mowing Areas&lt;/strong> are the areas which will be mowed. Each mowing area has a single outline and optional areas to exclude (e.g. static obstacles).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Docking Position&lt;/strong> is the position and orientation of your docking station. It needs to be close to a mowing area or navigation area. This is needed for the robot to find its way to the docking station.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Navigation Areas&lt;/strong> are areas similar to mowing areas (they consist of an outline and optionally exclusions). The mower is allowed to drive in these areas, but &lt;strong>won&amp;rsquo;t mow&lt;/strong>. Use these areas to connect mowing areas. Also, if your docking station is not close to a mowing area, you can use a navigation area to allow the robot to drive to the docking station.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now that the robot knows where it is located, and you know which areas we need to record, start recording your first map. In the following picture, you can see an example.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="record-outline">Record Outline&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="record_outline.jpg" alt="Record Outline">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drive the robot to the outline. Make sure that the robot is facing in &lt;strong>counterclockwise direction&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start the recording by pressing &lt;strong>Start Recording&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drive around the mowing area. Make sure that the GPS position stays fixed at all times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop the recording using &lt;strong>Stop Recording&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The outline should now turn green. This means it&amp;rsquo;s done recording, and you can move on to recording exclusions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="optional-record-exclusions">Optional: Record Exclusions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="record_obstacle.jpg" alt="Record Obstacle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your area has zones you want to exclude (e.g. static obstacles), you can record them like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drive the robot to the edge of the exclusion zone. Make sure that the robot is facing in &lt;strong>clockwise direction&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start the recording by pressing &lt;strong>Start Recording&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drive around the area to exclude. Make sure that the GPS position stays fixed at all times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop the recording using &lt;strong>Stop Recording&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The outline should now turn red. This means it&amp;rsquo;s done recording, and you can move on to recording more exclusions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="save-area">Save Area&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="save_mowing_area.jpg" alt="Save Area">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are happy with your recording, you can save the area. In order to do this, click the &lt;strong>Finish Area&lt;/strong> button. A dialog will appear asking if you want to save the area as mowing or navigation area. Alternatively, you can also discard the recording.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As soon as the area is saved, the area will turn solid. Mowing areas will be displayed in green, navigation areas will be shown in white.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="record-docking-position">Record Docking Position&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="record_docking_position.jpg" alt="Record Docking Position">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to record the docking position, do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Drive to a location about 2 m in front of your docking station.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure you have a GPS fix and press the &lt;strong>Record Docking&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now drive close to the docking station. The front wheels of the robot should be at the edge of the docking station. &lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t fully drive into the docking station!&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure you have a GPS fix and press the &lt;strong>Record Docking&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The app should move the &lt;strong>home&lt;/strong> icon to your current location. Now you can fully drive into the docking station.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="finish-recording">Finish Recording&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="start_mowing.jpg" alt="Start Mowing">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finish the process by pressing &lt;strong>Exit Recording&lt;/strong>. Now the mower should go to &lt;strong>IDLE&lt;/strong> mode. You should be able to start mowing by pressing the &lt;strong>Start&lt;/strong> button. The mower will undock, wait for GPS and mow the area.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>